Overview

A results-oriented, professional with 18+ years experience in the software industry focusing on customer success, sales, professional services, project delivery, marketing, product management, data analytics, and customer success. Skills include: customer-facing communication, problem solving, critical thinking, technical knowledge, high emotional IQ, Agile methods, and cross-team collaboration.

Experience

Johns Plumbing, Inc.; Chicago, Illinois (August 2018 - Present)

General Manager – Plumbing Contractor

- Responsible for managing both the revenue and cost elements of company's income statement.
 - Increased revenue by \$600,000+ through close management of large projects.
 - Reduced cost by \$100,000+ through optimizing office staff.
- Oversees the company's marketing and sales functions as well as the day-to-day operations of the business.
- Responsible for effective planning, delegating, coordinating, staffing, organizing, and decision-making to attain desirable profit-making results. Includes management of 15 direct reports with a complete staff of 53+.

Sandvine, Inc.; Des Plaines, Illinois (June 2007 - January 2018)

Service Delivery Manager (February 2017 - January 2018)

- Managed accounts (\$1M+) including professional services sales, support, and delivery of software-based solutions.
 - Primary Solution Architect for software-based solutions combining marketing, customer relationship data, user experience scoring, and individual targeted marketing.
 - Served as primary liaison with key customer's technical, marketing and executive staff.
 - Led a cross-functional team comprised of on-shore, near-shore, off-shore engineers, and support staff using Agile and Waterfall methods.

Pre-Sales Senior Solutions Architect (August 2009 - January 2017)

- Managed 100+ accounts in North America and the Caribbean including for professional service sales.
 - Served as point person for professional services during pre-sales engagement to ensure full understanding of customer needs and possible solutions Sandvine could offer.
 - Acted as technical expert for delivery teams during pre-sales, delivery, and post-deployment.
 - Responsible for gathering, defining, and documenting customer requirements.
 - Defined and identified potential barriers to success and developed solutions.
 - Created solution proposal, statement of work, effort estimate and cost projections for projects.
 - Provided solutions to apply predictive software-based marketing technology including data analytics, to define user experience and make targeted offers.
 - Led collaboration between multiple technology and marketing departments to ensure success in a competitive marketplace.

Senior Advanced Solutions Engineer (June 2007 – August 2009)

- Served as a main liaison of technical knowledge between Sandvine, Inc. and CableMatrix through acquisition.
- Ensured successful transition of product portfolio from CableMatrix into Sandvine offerings.
 - Collaborated with customers on the design, integration, configuration, testing, and deployment of solutions.
 - Guided account teams in addressing specific customer needs and developing custom solutions.
 - Validated technical solution designs through in-depth understanding of customer's technical requirements and network architecture.
 - Coordinated the technology and marketing experts to position the solution against competitors.

CableMatrix Technologies, Inc.; Des Plaines, Illinois (June 2005 – June 2007)

Product Manager and Senior Applications Engineer

- Key contributor in start-up that was successfully sold to Sandvine, Inc.
- Served as point person for product promotion during pre-sales engagement to ensure full understanding of customer needs and possible solutions.
 - Acted as technical expert for delivery teams during pre-sales, delivery, and post-deployment.

- Responsible for gathering, defining, and documenting customer requirements.
- Defined and identified potential barriers to success and developed solutions.
- Created solution proposal, statement of work, effort estimate and cost projections for projects.
- Provided solutions to apply predictive software-based marketing technology including data analytics, to define user experience and make targeted offers.
- Gathered market requirements and defined new products in the DOCSIS, WIMAX and IMS space while working closely with the Chief Technology Officer.
 - Promoted new and existing products and features to a variety of internal and external audiences.
 - Advocated and defined product modifications to create product differentiation.
 - Collaborated with an international team to manage product release planning across geographically diverse teams and secured internal resources for product team.
 - Created training materials for customers.
 - Managed lab trials at prospective client's facilities.
 - Managed interoperations certifications with development partners.

Motorola, Inc.; Libertyville, Illinois (March 2005 - June 2005)

Product Planning Analyst – Global Technical Marketing

- Managed and created software requirements for video telephony in a 3g network.
- Maintained video telephony feature roadmap.
- Created presentations to present future ideas to providers.
- Created Marketing and Product Requirement Documents.
- Managed Features in DOORS Software.

Teradyne, Inc. – Broadband Test Division; Deerfield, Illinois (May 2001 - March 2005)

Senior Applications Engineer – Product Marketing Group

- Conducted network and call center pre-sales work, setting delivery dates with customers.
- Served as the Technical Lead for proof-of-technology and proof-of-value trials at BellSouth, Comcast, RCN, and British Telecom
- Developed feature requirements for inclusion in marketing release plan.
- Drove the sales cycle at large telecommunications and cable companies including British Telecom and Comcast.

United States Naval Reserve (September 1989 – August 1997)

Hospital Corpsman Petty Officer Third Class

Served with Naval hospital unit, Naval Construction Battalion 'Sea-Bees' and Marine Corps Infantry unit.

Education

Keller Graduate School of Management; Lincolnshire, Illinois

Post Graduate Certificate - Business Administration

Purdue University; West Lafayette, Indiana and Kokomo, Indiana

Bachelor of Science - Telecommunication and Networking Technology

Associate of Science – Electrical Engineering Technology

Certifications

Amazon AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Organizational Engagement

Village of Villa Park - Parks & Recreation Commission (2018-2022)

Appointed to Village commission

Special Olympics Oak Brook (2017- present)

Annually lead a Polar Plunge team, raising \$3,000+ for Special Olympics athletes.

Child's Voice (2010 - present)

Volunteer at program and fundraising events to support children with hearing loss. Events include a Golf Tournament, Autumn Gala, 5K race, and family-focused events.